Guide to the Come!Unity Press Collection MSS.521
Fales Library and Special Collections
Come!Unity Press Collection
1972-1977
Fales Library and Special Collections
Come!Unity Press
MSS.521
1.5 Linear Feet in 1 record carton and 1 oversize flat box.
This collection consists of printed material produced by Come!Unity Press from 1972 to 1977. Pamphlets and posters addressing a variety of activism topics such as gay rights, women's rights, anti-facism, Native American rights, empowerment efforts for specific communities, and humanitarian crises in Vietnam, are represented in this assemblage of offset lithography prints. The pamphlets include poetry and appeals for social change on a broad and occasionally conflicting range of issues, including peace and anti-war efforts, gay rights and gay liberation, and international solidarity movements. Come!Unity Press was a gay anarchist collective that provided free printing materials and a shared living space for social and political activists. Operating from 13 East 17th Street in New York City, beginning in 1971, this 24-hour printing collective concentrated on publishing non-commercial alternative material on social and political justice issues. Come!Unity Press explained their purpose by printing slogans next to their logo stating "Survival by Sharing", "Unplug from Profit" and "Equal Access to the Poor, Printing Movement Alternatives to Imperialism, War and Rape."
Historical Note
Come!Unity Press was a gay anarchist collective print shop that provided free printing materials and a shared living space for social and political activists. Operating from 13 East 17th Street in New York City, beginning in 1971, this 24-hour printing collective concentrated on publishing non-commercial alternative material on social and political justice issues. The free printing materials were provided through donations and appeals to the public were included on each paper item produced. Come!Unity Press explained their purpose by printing slogans next to their logo, such as "Survival by Sharing", "Unplug from Profit" and "Equal Access to the Poor, Printing Movement Alternatives to Imperialism, War and Rape". Appeals for donations were printed on the front of posters and brochures stating that the publication was free but that donations would cover the cost of printing. The Come!Unity Press collective promoted their views of gay rights and anarchy with graphic design that included rainbow motifs and marijuana leaves.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from James Cummins Bookseller in May 2017. Prior provenance is unknown. The accession number associated with this collection is 2017.251
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of printed material produced by Come!Unity Press from 1972 to 1977. Pamphlets and posters addressing a variety of activism topics such as gay rights, women's rights, anti-facism, Native American rights, empowerment efforts for specific communities, and humanitarian crises in Vietnam, are represented in this assemblage of offset lithography prints. The pamphlets include poetry and appeals for social change on a broad and occasionally conflicting range of issues, including peace and anti-war efforts, gay rights and gay liberation, prisoners' rights and treatment, and international solidarity movements. Other posters in this collection advertise benefit events hosted by groups with an association to the collective, including the Quaker Project on Community Conflict, Freespace Alternate U., The People's Warehouse, WBAI-FM, and the Youth International Party.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from James Cummins Bookseller.
Cooperative societies.; Gay rights -- New York (State) -- New York.; Gay rights movement.; Arts and the poor; Social movements in art.; Graphic arts; Prints -- Technique
- Monetary Appeals, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Equal Rights for Gay People, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Wounded Knee News, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Poetry Pamphlets, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Social Justice Pamphlets, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Free School Poem Book, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Political Justice Pamphlets, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Children of the Night, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bakunin on Violence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Unemployment, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cooptation Blues, 1976-11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Attica is All of Us, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Free Space Alternative U, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Starvation in West Africa and Bangladesh, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Flyers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- A Gay Science Fiction Magazine, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- ANARCHOS, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Gay Pamphlets and Newspapers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Theater Pamphlets, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Philippines Information Bulletin, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- African Youth Movement for Liberation and Unity, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Food is for People, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Wounded Knee News no. 1, 1973-07 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Freespace Weekly Bulletin Vol. 3 no. 10, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Snake Poem and Image, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- En Avant!, 1975-03 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Call to War Tax Resistance, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Come to a Meeting on Suffering in Korea, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- A Million Calls to the White House to Stop the Bombing, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Peace on Earth. Nixon Has Fooled the American People, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Farm Workers Need Your Help, Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- McCarthy by Bob Pinkus, Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Parents and Neighbors in District 11, Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Benefit for the N.Y. Coalition to Defeat Senate Bill #1, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
- 10th Anniversary 4th of July Smoke-In, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Hey Brother Get Together, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Free Flowing River Committee, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
- The Lesbian Feminist, 1976-03, 1977-02 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Gay Youth Come Out!, Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
- American Anthropological Association Women's Caucus Newsletter, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- National Congress of Neighborhood Women Quarterly, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Come! Universe City Women's Firehouse, Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Emma Goldman Information Exchange, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Stop the Subway I Want to Get Off, Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
- The New York Street Theater Caravan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Equal Rights for Gay People, Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
- National Organization for Women N.Y.C. Chapter Sexuality Questionare, Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Loving Another Woman By Anne Koedt, Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- A Celebration of the Beguines, 1975-10-30, 1975-10-31 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Stop Rape, Gay Rights Action Coalition (Intro 475), Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
- I Killed the Fucking Guy Because He Raped Me. Demonstration in Support of Inez Garcia, Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Free Our Sisters in Cambodia, South Vietnam, Chile, U.S., Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Florynce Kennedy. Lesbian Feminist Liberation, Inc., Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Blow for Blow (Coup pour Coup) Free Association, Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Family Planning and Women, Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
- The Woman Identified Woman, Undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
- 810 Newsletter of the Gay People's Union NYU, Undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Come!Unity Press Flyer (Feedback), Undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Abraxas, Undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
- A Program for Feminist "Consciousness Raising", Undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Lesbian Resources in N.Y.C., Undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
- New York Lesbian Feminist Converence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
- VAC Vol.1 no. 6, Undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Street Poets of Amerika, Undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
- It's Four in the Morning, The End of December, Undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
- The Poor People's Pen Pal Party Line #2, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- An Evening of Films, Undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Poets in Focus, Undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
- The Latin Voice, 1976-09 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Alternative University Notice to the Community, Undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Manchester University Student Identification, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Benefit for the "Better Way Collective", Undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Senate Bill #1, Undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Free Assata Shakur, Undated (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Speak Out for America, Undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Voting Drives, Undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Religious Society of Friends Newsletter, 1973-03 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Freedom Committee For Sundiata Acoli, Undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Attica Memorial, 1975-09-12 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Speak Out on the Hard Times, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- University Heights Action Group Newsletter, 1975-05 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Clean Air by 1975, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 82)
- Dog Run Notes, 1973-04-23 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- What They're* Saying About "Ipi-Tombi" is a Lie, Undated (Box 1, Folder 84)
- New Year's Benefit Reading Schedule, Undated (Box 1, Folder 85)
- Gay Student Groups, 1977-01 (Box 1, Folder 86)
- Hard Times Hit Black Ny! Who's to Blame?, Undated (Box 1, Folder 87)
- Prisoners Strike for Peace, Undated (Box 1, Folder 88)
- The Wrinkle Fan Club Newsletter, 1973-11 (Box 1, Folder 89)
- Love Collective, Undated (Box 1, Folder 90)
- Free Radio Under Fire, Undated (Box 1, Folder 91)
- Ink? That Indomitable Redhead: Little Orphan Annie, Undated (Box 1, Folder 92)
- Big Bang Moment Foundation, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 93)
- The United Committee Against the Cutbacks, Undated (Box 1, Folder 94)
- The Free Association, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- Prospects for the Alternative Press, 1973-04-23 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- The Back Door, Undated (Box 1, Folder 97)
- U.S.B. Newsletter, 1976-03 (Box 1, Folder 98)
- The Brick, Undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
- Mainline 7, Undated (Box 1, Folder 100)
- Youth International Party Line, 1973-06 (Box 1, Folder 101)
- Free Bob Dylan? Rock fans Rights Committee, Undated (Box 1, Folder 102)
- Artists Meeting for Cultural Change, Undated (Box 1, Folder 103)
- The Underground Press Revue, Undated (Box 1, Folder 104)
- When the Prison Doors are Opened, The Real Dragon will Fly Out, Undated (Box 1, Folder 105)
- Vietnam March, 1973-01 (Box 1, Folder 106)
- Christopher Street Liberation Day March, Undated (Box 1, Folder 107)
- It's Cassie! Benefit for Dykes and Tykes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 108)
- Fund Raising Party for Mass Rep. Elaine Noble, 1976-06-05 (Box 1, Folder 109)
- Transmitted from Folsom Prison by Dr. Timothy Leary, Undated (Box 1, Folder 110)
- American Indian Movement, Undated (Box 1, Folder 111)
- Emergency Project for Saigon Civilian Prisoners, Undated (Box 1, Folder 112)
- Common Bread Lehman College Women's Center Publication, Undated (Box 1, Folder 113)
- Behind Bars, Undated (Box 1, Folder 114)
- TAP Technological American Party, 1973-11 (Box 1, Folder 115)
- The Eleventh Street Movement Energy Task Force, Undated (Box 1, Folder 116)
- Peoples Coalition for Peace and Justice, Undated (Box 1, Folder 117)
- How to Make a People's Credit Card Number, Undated (Box 1, Folder 118)
- Bread Not Loops, Report on the World Population Conference, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 119)
- Alternative Sources of Energy, 1972-09, 1972-10 (Box 1, Folder 120)
- Vocations for Social Change, Undated (Box 1, Folder 121)
- SMC Notes, 1977-04 (Box 1, Folder 122)
- Vocations for Social Change, Undated (Box 1, Folder 123)
- The Rites of Youth in the Values of Death, Undated (Box 1, Folder 124)
- Stop the B-1 Bomber, Undated (Box 1, Folder 125)
- New York City People's Life Fund, Undated (Box 1, Folder 126)
- AIM (The American Indian Movement), Undated (Box 1, Folder 127)
- Protestemos Contra El Regimen Yanqui - Balaguerista, Undated (Box 1, Folder 128)
- Comite de Defensa de los Prisioneros Politicos del Uruguay, Undated (Box 1, Folder 129)
- Free Learning Exchange, Undated (Box 1, Folder 130)
- Save the South Bronx Rally at Yankee Stadium, Undated (Box 1, Folder 131)
- Bowery Resident's Newsletter, Undated (Box 1, Folder 132)
- Daybreak the Daycare Journal, 1973-04 (Box 1, Folder 133)
- Mutual Aid Employment Agency, Undated (Box 1, Folder 134)
- Come!Unity Press Posters, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-5)